

Guilherme Borges Bastos

Full-stack Web Developer



Experience

2020-05 present

Full-stack Engineer

Swisscom AG

Swisscom is the #1 telecommunications company and one of the leading IT companies in Switzerland. Its products and services range from B2C products, such as Swisscom TV, to B2B IT solutions in multiple industries, such as Banking, Health, Energy, Entertainment, and Advertising.

2017-12 -2020-04

Software Engeneer / Pod Leader

QAT Global

At QAT Global, I was in charge of being the Pod Leader in the back-end side, working with Big Data Analysis for the largest American Water Technology provider. At QAT Global, During years, I've made sure that all the developers were applying the best patterns, practices, and standards needed for an enterprise application that required high availability, improving not only my technical skills but also the soft skills.

2017-01 -2017-11

Full-stack Web Developer

Skydreamer Startup

At Skydreamer Startup, I made part of the development team of the first European mobile application that turned traveling with friends into a 'Swipe and Match Game'. In a startup environment, with short deadlines periods and very limited resources, I was able to manage the team and finish the application. In September 2017, with the 'Beta' version running with real users, we went to TechCrunch Disrupt - San Francisco where we received an offer from an international sports and entertainment agency.

2014-07 -

Mobile Developer

2016-12 **Dee**v

At Deevo Studio, I had the chance to use the previously back-end knowledge combined with practical experience in JAVA development to accept the challenge to start an Android Department in the company, developing complex Android applications. Tens of Mobile apps were successfully delivered.

2011-01 -

Full-stack Developer

2014-06 **E-tática**

At E-tática I have worked to develop custom solutions for clients wholesale and retail, valuing the quality and continuity of projects in the medium and long term. Dozens of e-commerce were developed, including integrations with external ERPs.

2009-02 -

Webmaster intern

2010-12

Fácil Tecnologias

At Fácil Tecnologias LTDA, I got in touch with senior developers, learning best practices, patterns, and how to debate ideas and offer various solutions for the very same problem. It was the start point, a unique opportunity to turn theoretical knowledge into concrete solutions that were



Summary

Systems Analyst and a full stack developer with a large experience in prototyping, development, documentation of mobile and web applications. I have been working in cross-cultural teams delivering technical solutions to support business growth.



Personal Info

Website

https://guilhermeborgesbastos.com

GitHub

https://github.com/guilhermeborgesbastos

E-mail

guilhermeborgesbastos@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/guilherme borgesbastos/

Skype

guilhermeborgesbastos

Date of birth

1993-06-29

Address

Uberaba - Minas Gerais, Brazil



Skills

Java, Spring Boot, JPA, RESTful API, JUnit, Integration Test



Javascript, Typescript, Angular, AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Graph API



SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Elastic Search, NoSQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Geo-location DB



Version Control, Git ,Mercurial, Jenkins, AWS, DevOps, CI/CD, NPM, Maven, Docker



PHP, Slim Framework, Zend Framework, Laravel, Composer



being used by hundreds of people every day.

없

Education

2013-08 -2017-07 **University of Computer Science, FACTHUS, MG**

Higher Education Degree in Information System Analyst, with the final thesis published in a technology magazine.



Courses

2019-03 • M312: MongoDB Diagnostics and Debugging

2019-01 • M201: MongoDB Performance

2017-09 - **Deep Learning with TensorFlow**

2017-10

2016-12 - Complete React Native and Redux Course

2017-01

2015-06 - English Proficiency Exchange (Embassy English - San Diego, CA)

2015-09

2008-03

2008-01 - • SQL Database MasterClass (ENGENET - São Paulo, SP)

Magento, Wordpress, SEO, Structued Data

Mobile Development Android (JAVA)

React Native, React



Fabio Dexter, Deevo Studio - São Paulo

dexter@deevo.com.br fabio.dexter@gmail.com

Luis Felipe Salomão, E-tática

Agency - Rio de Janeiro

luisfelipe@e-tatica.com

Francisco Garcia de la Barrera, QAT Global, IT Solutions Architect - Omaha, Nebraska

coolfgb@hotmail.com